A Guide to the Peter F. Geithner papers FA1408
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation, Vietnam and China, 1973-1996; 3; 3.96 Cubic Feet 3 LTR size Hollinger boxes and 6 LGL size Hollinger boxes
  - Ford Foundation, China, 1986-1996; 2; 2.355 Cubic Feet About 1.25 LTR size Hollinger boxes and 4 LGL size Hollinger boxes
    - Johns Hopkins Foreign Policy Institute Policy Consensus Reports - U.S.-China Relations, 1989 (Box 112, Folder 1459)
    - Requested articles regarding China, 1988-1989 (Box 112, Folder 1460)
    - Reports and articles regarding China and U.S.-China relations, 1989-1990 (Box 112, Folder 1461-1462)
    - Articles regarding China economic reform, 1988-1989 (Box 113, Folder 1463)
    - Articles regarding China economic reform, 1989-1990 (Box 113, Folder 1464)
    - Articles regarding China social unrest and human rights abuses, 1989 (Box 113, Folder 1465)
    - Articles regarding China repression of political dissidents and U.S. response, 1989 (Box 113, Folder 1466)
    - Christian Science Monitor articles regarding China repression of political dissidents and international response, 1989 (Box 113, Folder 1467)
    - Articles regarding China pro-democracy protestors and repression of political dissidents, 1989 (Box 113, Folder 1468)
    - Asia Society - Reception and Luncheon in Honor of China Minister of Foreign Affairs Qian Qichen invitees, 1990 (Box 113, Folder 1469)
    - Articles regarding China repression of political dissidents and U.S. response, 1989-1990 (Box 113, Folder 1470)
    - Ford Foundation and personal correspondence discussing Tiananmen Square protests, 1989 May (Box 113, Folder 1471)
    - Articles regarding China pro-democracy protestors, 1989 (Box 113, Folder 1472)
    - Articles regarding China pro-democracy protestors and repression of political dissidents, 1989 (Box 113, Folder 1473)
    - Articles regarding China pro-democracy protestors and repression of political dissidents, 1989-1990 (Box 113, Folder 1474)
    - The Democratic Pluralism Initiative (DPI) - Open Markets - Open Societies State Paper, 1989 December 14 (Box 113, Folder 1475)
    - Articles and other types of publications regarding China, 1987-1990 (Box 113, Folder 1476)
    - Asia Society Meet the Author Series - Shen Tong, Almost A Revolution, 1990 (Box 113, Folder 1477)
    - Reports and articles regarding China economic reform and political change, 1986-1990 (Box 113, Folder 1478-1479)
    - Gordon White - Chinese Economic Reform and the Rise of Civil Society draft, 1990 (Box 113, Folder 1480)
    - Various types of publications regarding China economic reform and other China-related topics, 1989-1991 (Box 113, Folder 1481)
    - Nick Menzies memo - Meeting with the Yunnan Uplands Management (YUM) Program Leading Group, 1991 March (Box 114, Folder 1482)
    - Various types of publications regarding China, 1990-1991 (Box 114, Folder 1483)
    - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations (NCUSCR) draft letter to Head of China Foreign Affairs Office Gao Rui, 1991 March 28 (Box 114, Folder 1484)
    - Reports and articles regarding China, 1991 (Box 114, Folder 1485)
    - Johns Hopkins University Notice - Broadening the Mission of the Hopkins-Nanjing Center, 1991 February (Box 114, Folder 1486)
    - Articles regarding China economic reform, 1991-1992 (Box 114, Folder 1487)
    - America-China Society Symposium notes, 1992 April 30 (Box 114, Folder 1488)
    - Articles regarding China intellectuals and dissidents, 1991 (Box 114, Folder 1489)
    - U.S. Congress Joint Economic Committee (JEC) hearing on China economy, 1990 (Box 114, Folder 1490)
    - Cyril Lin correspondence, 1991 (Box 114, Folder 1491)
    - Miscellaneous materials regarding U.S.-China relations, 1989-1990 (Box 114, Folder 1492)
    - Global environmental programs and articles regarding U.S. and China energy policies, 1990 (Box 114, Folder 1493)
    - Douglas Murray correspondence, 1990 (Box 114, Folder 1494)
    - Nay Htun comments on China environmental policy meeting and China Business Review (CBR) interview, circa 1990 (Box 114, Folder 1495)
    - Articles and reports regarding China environmental issues, 1990 (Box 114, Folder 1496)
    - Articles and speech regarding China politics, 1990-1991 (Box 114, Folder 1497)
    - Peter Harris forwarded speech and report, 1990 November (Box 114, Folder 1498)
    - Publication and articles regarding China legal system and economic reform, 1991 (Box 114, Folder 1499)
    - Guocang Huan memo - The Chinese Military, 1991 April (Box 114, Folder 1500)
    - Articles regarding U.S.-China relations and China economic reform, 1991-1992 (Box 114, Folder 1501-1502)
    - Pacific Trade and Development Conference (PAFTAD) notes, 1992 May (Box 114, Folder 1503)
    - Articles regarding U.S.-China relations and China economic reform, 1990-1991 (Box 114, Folder 1504)
    - U.S.-focused articles and speech, 1990 (Box 114, Folder 1505)
    - World Bank News issues regarding global economy and development, 1990 September (Box 114, Folder 1506)
    - Reports regarding U.S.-China relations and China economic reform, 1991 (Box 114, Folder 1507)
    - University of Southern California (USC) International Business Education and Research Program (IBEAR) - Gary Zou, 1991 (Box 114, Folder 1508-1509)
    - Peter T. Knight memo - Meeting at China Central Radio and TV University, 1993 March 29 (Box 115, Folder 1510)
    - Articles regarding China politics and economic reform, 1992 (Box 115, Folder 1511)
    - Report for the Ford Foundation on Research and Training for Rural Development in Poor Areas of China, Peter Nolan and John Sender, 1991-1992 (Box 115, Folder 1512)
    - Harvard Institute for International Development (HIID) Research Review, Vol. 5, No. 2, 1992 (Box 115, Folder 1513)
    - Henry Luce Foundation U.S.-China Cooperative Research Program - 1993 competition proposals list, undated (Box 115, Folder 1514)
    - The Heritage Foundation Talking Points - Bush's Trip to Canberra, Singapore, Seoul and Tokyo: Reaffirming America's Commitment to Asia, 1991 December 19 (Box 115, Folder 1515)
    - University of Pittsburgh Department of Economics - Reports regarding China economy, 1991-1992 (Box 115, Folder 1516)
    - Harvard Institute for International Development (HIID) Research Review, Vol. 4, No. 1, 1990 (Box 115, Folder 1517)
    - Assistant Secretary of State Richard H. Solomon statement to Senate Foreign Relations Subcommittee on East Asian and Pacific Affairs, 1991 May 17 (Box 115, Folder 1518)
    - America-China Society Symposium, 1992 (Box 115, Folder 1519)
    - Articles regarding U.S.-China relations and China economic reform, 1991-1992 (Box 115, Folder 1520)
    - Council on Foreign Relations - Asia Studies Contemporary Issues Series: China, 1991 (Box 115, Folder 1521)
    - University of California Institute on Global Conflict and Cooperation (IGCC) - The China Circle: Economics and Electronics in the People's Republic of China (PRC), Taiwan, and Hong Kong second review draft, 1995 (Box 115, Folder 1522)
    - Reports regarding China international relations and agriculture, 1996 (Box 115, Folder 1523)
    - Articles and reports regarding China international relations, 1995-1996 (Box 115, Folder 1524-1525)
    - American Enterprise Institute (AEI)/Shanghai Institute for International Studies (SIIS) - New Ideas and Concepts in Sino-American Relations Conference Report, circa 1992 (Box 116, Folder 1526)
    - Science Applications International Corporations (SAIC) - Visit to Beijing, circa 1996 (Box 116, Folder 1527)
    - Agreement between Russia, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, and China on Confidence Building in the Military Field in the Border Area, 1996 June 24 (Box 116, Folder 1528)
    - Committee of 100 Annual Conference - U.S.-China Relations into the Next Century, 1996 (Box 116, Folder 1529)
    - Articles and reports regarding U.S.-China relations and China politics, 1995-1996 (Box 116, Folder 1530)
    - China and the Strategic Quadrangle: Foreign Policy Continuity in an Age of Discontinuity by David M. Lampton, 1993 December 29 (Box 116, Folder 1531)
    - Articles and reports regarding China politics and other China-related topics, 1993-1996 (Box 116, Folder 1532)
    - Report and compiled H.H. Dalai Lama, U.S. Congressional leadership, and President Bill Clinton correspondence regarding Tibet, 1988-1994 (Box 116, Folder 1533)
    - Reports and notes from conferences regarding China economy, 1992-1996 (Box 116, Folder 1534)
    - U.S. Department of State Dispatch, Vol. 4, No. 24 - China: Most-Favored-Nation Status, 1993 June 14 (Box 116, Folder 1535)
    - China Emerges film - Visualization and treatment, undated (Box 116, Folder 1536)
    - Articles and reports regarding U.S.-China relations and other China-related topics, 1995-1996 (Box 116, Folder 1537)
    - Correspondence regarding Asia Pacific Roundtable Gender and Security Panel, 1995-1996 (Box 116, Folder 1538)
    - Articles regarding NGOs in China and China economic reform, 1995 (Box 116, Folder 1539)
    - Economic Dynamism and Political Fragility in Northeast Asia: Prospects for the 21st Century and Geithner notes, 1995 (Box 116, Folder 1540)
    - Articles and reports regarding China, 1991-1996 (Box 116, Folder 1541)
    - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations (NCUSCR) resource list and newsletters, 1990-1995 (Box 116, Folder 1542)
    - Articles and reports regarding China economy, 1992 (Box 117, Folder 1543)
    - Stanley B. Lubman correspondence, 1992 (Box 117, Folder 1544)
    - Articles and reports regarding China politics and China economy, 1991-1994 (Box 117, Folder 1545-1546)
    - Congressional Research Service (CRS) Reports for Congress regarding U.S.-China relations, 1991-1992 (Box 117, Folder 1547)
    - Articles and reports regarding China political and economic reform, 1991-1993 (Box 117, Folder 1548-1549)
    - China/Asia-Pacific articles and reports, 1994-1995 (Box 117, Folder 1550-1551)
- Ford Foundation, Asia-Pacific regional issues, 1994-1999; 4; 1.7 Cubic Feet 2 LTR size Hollinger boxes and 2 LGL size Hollinger boxes
  Series consists of a group of Peter F. Geithner's professional files that was originally stored in a set of boxes titled Ford Foundation files and diaries. During collection accessioning, mold was discovered on most of the content within those boxes. This prompted archivists to remove all contaminated documents from the collection for mold remediation treatment. Consequently, the amount of content was reduced to less than half of its original size. Significant contextual information that may provide insight into why Geithner grouped these records in this way is therefore unavailable for the time being.
  Such information could clarify Geithner's use of the title, Ford Foundation Files, 8/95-8/97, for the two boxes of material that could be processed and opened to public use. The combination of the title and date may seem confusing when considering that Geithner retired from Ford in 1996. Moreover, some of the content within the boxes originates from as late as 1999, several years after Geithner's retirement. It was decided during processing to keep the records as part of their own series and to retain the Ford Foundation title in order to represent Geithner's original system of arrangement that, due to the removed material, could not be fully understood. The series description was simply expanded to better represent the content of the records.
  Records within the series document Geithner's engagement with issues involving the Asia-Pacific region in the mid and late 1990s such as the transfer of Hong Kong back to China and the 1997 Asian financial crisis.
  - Asia Society Asian Update - Hong Kong's Transition: Context and Implications from Both Sides of the Pacific, 1997 April (Box 118, Folder 1552)
  - Asia Pacific Philanthropy Consortium (APPC) - Comparative Nonprofit Law Project Second Conference for Legal Specialists Country Papers, 1997 (Box 118, Folder 1553-1555)
  - Articles and reports regarding Hong Kong transfer, 1996-1997 (Box 118, Folder 1556)
  - Asia Society Asian Update - Asia's Stake in Hong Kong drafting, 1996-1997; File contains a floppy disk (folder 1557). The floppy disk was found in an envelope from the Asia Society and had a sticky note on it that with the text "Asian Update - 4/10/97 - (PFG)". The disk likely contains a copy of the Asia Society Asian Update - Hong Kong's Transition: Context and Implications from Both Sides of the Pacific publication. (Box 118, Folder 1557-1559)
  - Asian Update - 4/10/97 - (PFG) floppy disk (Box 118, Folder 1557)
  - Asia Pacific Agenda Project (APAP) Bali Forum, 1996-1997 (Box 118, Folder 1560)
  - Asia Pacific Agenda Project (APAP) Bali Forum conference papers, 1996 (Box 119, Folder 1561-1563)
  - Promotional material for education and research institutions, 1996 (Box 119, Folder 1564)
  - Council on Foundations - Corporate Citizenship in Asia Pacific Conference reports, 1997 (Box 119, Folder 1565)
  - Council on Foundations - Joint Working Group on International Corporate Philanthropy, 1994-1997 (Box 119, Folder 1566)
  - Council on Foundations - Joint Working Group on International Corporate Philanthropy Fourth Planning Meeting, 1994-1995 (Box 119, Folder 1567-1569)
  - Council on Foundations - Joint Working Group on International Corporate Philanthropy Third Planning Meeting, 1994 (Box 119, Folder 1570-1571)
  - Council on Foundations - Joint Working Group on International Corporate Philanthropy, 1995 (Box 120, Folder 1572-1573)
  - Council on Foundations - Joint Working Group on International Corporate Philanthropy Second Planning Meeting, 1994 (Box 120, Folder 1574)
  - Harvard University - Unintended Social Consequences of Chinese Economic Reform Conference papers, 1997 (Box 120, Folder 1575-1577)
  - 1997 Asian financial crisis - China, 1998 (Box 120, Folder 1578)
  - 1997 Asian financial crisis - Europe, 1998 (Box 120, Folder 1579)
  - Reports regarding 1997 Asian financial crisis, 1998-1999 (Box 120, Folder 1580)
  - 1997 Asian financial crisis - International Monetary Fund (IMF), 1998 (Box 120, Folder 1581)
  - 1997 Asian financial crisis - Social and political consequences and implications, 1998 (Box 120, Folder 1582)
  - Asian Development Bank - Report on Proposed Loans and Technical Assistance Grants to Indonesia, 1998 June (Box 121, Folder 1583)
  - J. Soedradjad Dijwandono papers regarding Indonesia economic recovery, 1999 (Box 121, Folder 1584)
  - 1997 Asian financial crisis - Indonesia, 1997-1998 (Box 121, Folder 1585-1586)
  - 1997 Asian financial crisis - South Korea, 1998-1999 (Box 121, Folder 1587)
  - 1997 Asian financial crisis - Japan, 1998 (Box 121, Folder 1588)
  - 1997 Asian financial crisis - Thailand, 1998-1999 (Box 121, Folder 1589)
  - 1997 Asian financial crisis - Thailand, 1998 (Box 121, Folder 1590)
  - 1997 Asian financial crisis - Other countries in Asia, 1998 (Box 121, Folder 1591)
  - 1997 Asian financial crisis - Asia-Pacific regional institutions, 1998 (Box 121, Folder 1592)
  - 1997 Asian financial crisis - United States, 1998 (Box 121, Folder 1593)
  - Articles and reports regarding the 1997 Asian financial crisis, 1998-1999 (Box 121, Folder 1594)
  - Articles and reports regarding the 1997 Asian financial crisis, 1998-1999 (Box 121, Folder 1595-1596)
- Professional and personal files, third run, 1982-2005; 5; 6.301 Cubic Feet 18 LTR size Hollinger boxes
  Several different organizational schemes and content groupings were identified for the collection material originally stored in a run of untitled boxes. They became the basis for the five subseries imposed during processing.
  Series 5. Subseries 1. Philanthropy, 1994-2005
  Series 5. Subseries 2. Subject files, 1982-2005
  Series 5. Subseries 3. Correspondence with individuals, 1995-2005
  Series 5. Subseries 4. Philanthropic organizations and research institutions, 1995-2004
  Series 5. Subseries 5. Reports, articles, and publications, 1983-2004
  Series consists of a group of records that was originally stored in an untitled set of boxes. Like Series 1 and 2, it contains both professional and personal material.
  Peter F. Geithner appears to have imposed consistent content-related groupings and arrangement schemes to organize the documents. These distinct segments are described as five individual subseries in the finding aid. The first subseries contains files regarding the field of international and region-specific philanthropy. Subseries 2 consists of a group of subject files, and Subseries 3 consists of a group of correspondence files. Records regarding Geithner's work with individual foundations and research institutions can be found in Subseries 4, and finally, Subseries 5 contains an assortment of various reports, articles, and publications.
  Most of the content within the series originates from between 1996 and 2004. This is a period that followed right after Geithner retired from the Ford Foundation.
  - Philanthropy, 1994-2005; 1; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 LTR size Hollinger boxes
    Subseries documents Peter F. Geithner's involvement in efforts by the field of international and region-specific philanthropy to discuss, analyze, and improve non-profit programming, management, and strategy rather than his work with specific philanthropic projects, devised and managed by foundations and other civil society organizations. It contains reports, articles, and directories that describe non-profit organizations, trends, and issues during the time in which the records were created. Furthermore, it holds files that Geithner created to document his participation in philanthropy-related meetings, workshops, and conferences.
    Correspondence, reports, and other types of records within the subseries reveal that during this time period, individuals and organizations involved in civil society contemplated such subjects as corporate social responsibility, funds management, and non-profit organization self-regulation and transparency.
    - United Nations Fund for International Partnerships (UNFIP) - Working Luncheon on Legislative Tax Benefits for Giving, 2001 (Box 122, Folder 1597)
    - Asia Pacific Philanthropy Consortium (APPC) Conference - Strengthening Philanthropy in the Asia Pacific: An Agenda for Action background papers, 2001 (Box 122, Folder 1598)
    - SEAL: Social Economy and Law Journal, Vol. 7, No. 1 - Percentage Philanthropy: A Special Issue, 2004 (Box 122, Folder 1599)
    - Nonprofit Coordinating Committee of New York (NPCC) Annual Meeting, 2001-2002 (Box 122, Folder 1600)
    - Correspondence regarding U.S. foundation strategy, 2004 June 9 (Box 122, Folder 1601)
    - Insights in Action - The U.S. Nonprofit Support Infrastructure, 2004 (Box 122, Folder 1602)
    - 2000 Directory of International NGOs Supporting Work in China, 1999 October (Box 122, Folder 1603)
    - United Nations Fund for International Partnerships (UNFIP) - Working Luncheon on Legislative Tax Benefits for Giving, 2001 June 18 (Box 122, Folder 1604)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Meeting - "Global Philanthropy: Where are we? Where do we want go? How do we want to get there?", 2001 (Box 122, Folder 1605)
    - China NPO Network - NPO Training and Capacity Building Workshop in China, 2001 (Box 122, Folder 1606)
    - Directory of Grant-Making Foundations in Japan, 2000 (Box 122, Folder 1607)
    - Corporate involvement in community and economic development, 1994-2002 (Box 123, Folder 1608-1609)
    - Articles regarding corporate philanthropy, 2000-2003 (Box 123, Folder 1610)
    - Corporate social responsibility (CSR), 1996-2001 (Box 123, Folder 1611-1612)
    - Corporate social responsibility (CSR) and The Aspen Institute Initiative for Social Innovation trough Business (ISIB), 2000-2003 (Box 123, Folder 1613)
    - Philanthropy - General, 1996-2003 (Box 123, Folder 1614-1615)
    - Articles and reports regarding philanthropy and corporate social responsibility (CSR), 1998-2001 (Box 124, Folder 1616)
    - Philanthropy conferences, 1997 (Box 124, Folder 1617-1618)
    - Asia Foundation Asian Perspectives Series - Advancing Corporate Governance Reform in Asia, 2002 (Box 124, Folder 1619)
    - Pamphlet and journal issue regarding philanthropy, 2000 (Box 124, Folder 1620)
    - NPO fund management, 1998-1999 (Box 124, Folder 1621)
    - NGOs - Self-regulation and transparency, 2000-2002 (Box 124, Folder 1622)
    - NGOs - Self-regulation and transparency, 2000-2002 (Box 124, Folder 1623)
    - Civil society - General, 1997-2005 (Box 124, Folder 1624-1625)
    - Civil society - Asia, 1994-2005 (Box 124, Folder 1626-1627)
  - Subject files, 1982-2005; 2; 1.71 Cubic Feet About 4.5 LTR size Hollinger boxes
    Subseries contains a group of records organized by the first letter of the document's subject. An individual file was created for each letter or group of letters from the alphabet. Files are arranged in alphabetical order, but subjects within a file are not ordered alphabetically. Subjects were determined by the records' creator, and they include names of topics, organizations, and individuals. File level scope and content notes have been added in order to provide researchers better insight into the contents of individual subject files.
    - A - Subjects, 1982-2003 (Box 125, Folder 1628-1630)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: The American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS); The Asia Foundation; The Asia Society; The Aspen Institute; Peter F Geithner's daughter and son-in-law, Sara and Andrew Adam; John Ambler; and the Atlantic Council of the United States.
    - B - Subjects, 1996-2004 (Box 125, Folder 1631-1633)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Bangladesh; Bhutan; Peter Bottelier; Prahlad K. Basu; Radhika Balakrishnan; Srilatha Batliwala; and Frank A. Bauman.
    - C - Subjects, 1991-2005 (Box 125, Folder 1634-1636)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Praveen K. Chaudry; China; The Centre for Modern Chinese Studies; The Chinese Academy of Social Sciences (CASS); and Cambodia.
    - D - Subjects, 1997-2002 (Box 125, Folder 1637-1638)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Jingping Ding; J. Soedradjad Djiwandono; and the American Ditchtley Foundation.
    - E - Subjects, 1997-2004 (Box 126, Folder 1639)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Paul Evans and the East-West Center.
    - F - Subjects, 1996-2004 (Box 126, Folder 1640-1643)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: The Ford Foundation; Alan Feinstein; Rosemary Morales-Fernholz; and Jose Ireneu dos Remedios Furtado.
    - G - Subjects, 1997-2004 (Box 126, Folder 1644-1645)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: The Ghana Education Project (GEP); The German Marshal Fund; Christina Geithner; Gan Dongyu; and Allan E. Goodman.
    - H - Subjects, 1996-2004 (Box 126, Folder 1646-1647)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Hamilton, Rabinovitz and Alschuler; Jon K. Hartzell; Peter Harris; Mehlika Hoodbhoy; Susan Hubbard; Lowell Hardin; and Human rights.
    - I - Subjects, 1994-2004 (Box 126, Folder 1648)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: The Institute of Public Administration (IPA); India; and Indonesia.
    - J - Subjects, 1996-2005 (Box 127, Folder 1649-1650)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Japan and Devaki and Lakshmi Jain.
    - K - Subjects, 1996-2003 (Box 127, Folder 1651-1652)